mytravelshanti.com 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Mytravelshanti Policies | Mytravelshanti

**Introduction:**

The Privacy Policy covers the practices for handling and securing your Personal Information by Mytravelshanti.com.

This Privacy Policy is applicable to persons who purchase any product or services from Mytravelshanti.com through any Sales Channel of Offline or Online. This Privacy Policy also applies to all the persons visiting Mytravelshanti.com’s office.

As a user or customer of Mytravelshanti.com, the person agrees with this Privacy Policy and the terms and conditions mentioned herein.

This privacy statement does not apply to the websites, mobile sites and mobile apps of our other third parties, even if their websites are linked to Mytravelshanti.com Website. We recommend you review the privacy statements of the other parties with whom you choose to interact.

What Personal Information we collect from you and how we use it?

‘Personal Information’ means and includes all information that can be linked to a specific individual or to identify any individual, such as name, address, mailing address, telephone number, email address, information about the travel, bookings, passengers, and any and all details that may be necessary from the customer.

No personal information is required to be submitted to our website unless you decide to make an enquiry or purchase or signup for of our e-mail newsletters or other services as described below

When you visit Mytravelshanti.com’s website, we may collect information regarding the domain and host from which you access the internet, the internet protocol address of the computer or internet service provider you are using, and anonymous statistical data. The website and mobile site uses cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Personal Information will not be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information.

**Making a Purchase**

As of now we do not have a payment gateway installed on our website, hence no information is collected.

**Member Registration**

If you choose to become a registered member of Website, you must provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, a unique login name, password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including but not limited to:

1.Personal identification

2.To complete the travel and stay reservations

3.To allow us to contact you for customer service purposes, if necessary

4.To customize the content of our website, mobile site and mobile app to strive to meet your specific needs; and

5.To make product or other improvements;

6\. To confirm your new member registration and each reservation you make.

**Member Profile:**

We just ask for some basic details like your name, contact details, etc. and do not ask for sensitive information.

**Surveys:**

Mytravelshanti.com values opinions and comments from members, so we frequently conduct surveys, both online and offline. Participation in these surveys is entirely optional. Typically, the information is aggregated, and used to make improvements to website, mobile site and mobile app and its services and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for members. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey.

**Promotions & Sweepstakes:**

Mytravelshanti.com sometimes sponsors promotions and sweepstakes to give members the opportunity to win great travel and travel – related prizes. Information collected by us for such activities may include contact information and survey questions. We use contact information to notify contest winners and survey information to develop promotions and product improvements. We may also send you monthly newsletters and exclusive promotions offering special deals. However, you may choose at any time to no longer receive these types of e – mail messages by unsubscribing from the list or sending us an email on the address provided in the mailer.

**Automatic Logging of Session Data:**

We automatically log generic information about your devices connection to the Internet, which we call “session data”, that is anonymous and not linked to any Personal Information. Session data consists of things such as IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the user while on the device. An IP address is a number that lets devices attached to the internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the website the user wishes to view. We collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the website/ mobile site/ mobile app, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the website/ mobile site/ mobile app, how long visitors are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. Although such information does not identify any visitor personally, it is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor’s Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your device’s hard drive. Cookies are only read by the server that placed them and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses or harvest your Personal Information. The use of cookies is very common on the Internet.

Mytravelshanti.com’s use of cookies is similar to that of any other reputable online companies. No personally identifiable information (PII) about you (e.g., name, address, etc.) is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by a website or mobile site. Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our website and mobile site.

For personalization of experience – these cookies allow you to log in without having to type your log – in name each time (only your password is needed); we may also use such cookies to display an advertisement to you while you are on the Website or mobile site or to send you promotional/special offer emails – assuming you have not opted out of receiving such emails. This information is not passed to any third party, and is used by us to provide you with a better user experience on the Website and mobile site.

The third – party advertising companies or advertisement providers may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. Any such information is anonymous. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to our websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. No PII is collected during this process. The information is anonymous, and does not link online actions to an identifiable person.

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies. Of course, by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. Mytravelshanti.com supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking Mytravelshanti.com cookies may disable certain features on the website and mobile site, and may make it impossible to purchase or use certain services available on the website and mobile site. The decision is entirely up to you.

**Others:**

From time to time we may add or enhance services available on the Website. To the extent these services are provided, and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilitate the service requested. Such information may be stored to assist us in making the Website the better and easier to use.

**With whom your Personal Information is shared?**

When you reserve or purchase travel services through us, we must provide certain of your Personal Information to the airline, hotel, car – rental agency, travel agency or other involved third party to enable the successful fulfilment of your travel arrangements.

However, individual customer names or other Personal Information are not sold or tent to third parties except sharing of such information with our alliance partners or vendors who are engaged by us for providing various promotional and other benefits to our customers from time to time basis their booking history with us.

We may also share certain filtered Personal Information to our business partners who may contact the customers to offer certain products or services (which may include free or paid products / services) which will enable the customer to have better travel experience or to avail certain benefits specially made for Mytravelshanti.com Customers. Examples of such partners are entities offering travel insurance, insurance cover against loss of wallet, banking cards or similar sensitive information etc.

We use non – personally identifiable information in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analysis of the collective characteristics and behavior of our customers and visitors. Based on this data anonymous statistical information may be provided to suppliers, advertisers, affiliates and other current and potential Business partners. We may also use such aggregate data to inform these third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked on links to their websites.

Mytravelshanti.com, may occasionally hire a third party to act on our behalf for projects such as market – research surveys and contest – entry processing and will provide information to these third parties specifically for use in connection with these projects. The information provided to such third parties, alliance partners, or vendors are protected by confidentiality agreements signed before handing over the information and such information is used solely for completing the specific project.

**How you can opt-out of receiving our promotional e-mails?**

At any time, you may unsubscribe from our newsletters or promotional services. You will occasionally receive e-mail updates from us about special offers and deals, any new Mytravelshanti.com services, and other noteworthy items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. If you wish not to receive them, please click on the “unsubscribe” link or follow the instructions in each e – mail message or send us an email at contact@mytravelshanti.com with ‘Unsubscribe’ in the subject line.

**What other information should I know about my privacy?**

Website, mobile site and mobile app contain links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which Mytravelshanti.com has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords, and your membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you’re online.

In addition to the circumstances described above, Mytravelshanti.com may disclose the member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of Mytravelshanti.com or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, directors or officers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities. In addition, if Mytravelshanti.com or substantially all of its assets are acquired, our customer information will most likely also be transferred in connection with such acquisition.

We review our **Privacy Policy** from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version.

If you have any concerns/queries/questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please email it to contact@mytravelshanti.com and Mytravelshanti.com will respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries.

Thank you for using the Website. We hope you enjoy visiting it.
